Finding Aid for the Ralph Nelson Papers LSC.0875
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ralph Nelson papers
1940-1983
UCLA Library Special Collections
Nelson, Ralph
LSC.0875
65.0 Linear Feet (116 boxes, 25 oversize boxes, and 7 cartons)
Ralph Nelson (1916-1987) was an actor, director, producer, and playwright. He wrote the play Mail call (winner of the 1943 John Golden prize and National Theatre awards), and won National Theatre awards for Angels weep and The wind is ninety. In 1956, he won a Emmy award for direction of Requiem for a heavyweight (1956), and in 1964, the Golden Globes Humanitarian award for directing Lilies of the field. The collection consists of television and motion picture shooting scripts, production files, films, tape recordings, phonograph records, scrapbooks, prints, personal memorabilia, and related printed material of Ralph Nelson. Scripts include Requiem for a heavyweight, The director, Father Goose, and Lilies of the field.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ralph Nelson, 1964-83.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942334843606533
Biography
Nelson was born on August 12, 1916 in New York City; attended public school there; became an actor, director, producer, and playwright; worked as an actor, 1933-41; directed for NBC-TV, 1948-49, and for CBS-TV, 1949-52; president of Rainbow Productions in Los Angeles beginning in 1959; wrote the play Mail call (winner of the 1943 John Golden prize and National Theatre awards); also won National Theatre awards for Angels weep and The wind is ninety; won 1956 Emmy award for direction of Requiem for a heavyweight, and in 1964 the Golden Globes Humanitarian award for directing Lilies of the field; also wrote screenplays for The man in the funny suit, The flight of the doves, and The wrath of God; other films directed or produced by Nelson include Father Goose, Counterpoint, and Charley; he died on December 21, 1987 in Santa Monica, California.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of television and motion picture shooting scripts, production files, films, tape recordings, phonograph records, scrapbooks, prints, personal memorabilia, and related printed material of Ralph Nelson, motion picture and television writer and director. Scripts include Requiem for a heavyweight, The director, Father Goose, and Lilies of the field.
Items Removed from Collection
Items Transferred to the Film and Television Archive, UCLA
Flight of the Doves (16mm print - 3 reels).
Charly (16mm print - 3 reels).
"Requiem for a Heavyweight," Playhouse 90 (16mm print - 3 reels).
Soldier Blue (16mm print - 3 reels).
The Man in the Funny Suit (16mm print - 1 reel).
The Two Worlds of Charley Gordon (16mm print - 1 reel).
Kinescope: Mama Kinescope of Mama and The Carpenter.
"The Richest Man In Bogota" (Du Pont Show Of The Week).
The Outlaw's Reckoning.
"The Brandenburg Gate" (Motorola TV Hour).
"The Trial of Captain Wirz" (Climax).
"This Happy Breed" (Ford Star Jubilee) Reel no.2 only.
"Hamlet" (Du Pont Show Of The Week).
Cinderella.
Stock Footage: Bergen, Norway (Fjord shots and Bonfire), London (Piccadilly Circus and Scotland Yard), View from Stavangerfjord - seagulls, and Shots made in Stockholm and Copenhagen.
Items Cataloged
A portfolio of Hirschfeld: impressions of the play of the week (Limited Edition). Hirschfeld, Al (07-AFH-4287). Available at Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
Illustrations for The complete works of Shakespeare, edited by William Cullen Bryant. Philadelphia, c.1886. Illustrations by Felix Octavius Carr Darley, 1822-1888 (*** PR 2883 D249i). Available at Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
Portfolio of William Blake's paintings for Paradise Lost. New York, 1947 (**NC 1115 B58p). Available at Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
Items Withdrawn by Ralph Nelson
Mama series: "Along Came A Spider," "T.R.'S New Home," "He Jests at Scars" and Makeup test.
Requiem for a Heavyweight and Man in a Funny Suit programs.
Items Sent to Music Library:
Red Seal records by: Caruso, Tettrazini, Melba, Chaliapin, McCormack, etc. (78 rpm) Originals, at $3.00 each (65 total).
Items not Received
One framed Lithograph by John Groth.
Oil painting by Jack Smith for Fate is the Hunter.
Lilies of the Field Script.
Taped Shows Not Received
Justice.
The Richest Man in Bogota (DuPont Show of the Week), June 1962.
The New March of Dimes Presents What About Linda? (a one hour television film), January 1961.
The Outlaw's Reckoning.
The Brandenburg Gate (ABC), One Hour Show.
The Trial of Captain Wirz.
This Happy Breed.
Hamlet.
Phone Call for Matt Quade (Climax).
Mama Television Series: "Along Came a Spider", "Penny Candy", and "The Night the Animals Talked". [See Box 78].
T.R.'s New Home.
Television producers and directors -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Motion picture producers and directors -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Screenwriters -- United States -- Archives.; Television plays.; Film scripts.; Nelson, Ralph -- Archives
- Books, Magazines, and Tapes
  - First Editions
    - Player's Blue Book compiled by A.D. Storms., 1901 (Box 22)
    - The Wind is Ninety - a play in 3 acts by Captain Ralph Nelson., (6 copies) (Box 6)
    - Hamlet., February 1959 (Box 2)
      Scope and Contents note
      An adaptation by Ralph Nelson and Michael Benthell for presentation on the CBS-TV network by The Old Vic Company.
    - Reinhardt Und Seine Buhne - Berlin., 1920 (Box 22)
    - Walter's Sketch Book Of The Players., n.d. (Box 22)
    - Director Ralph Nelson's cast book. (Box 6)
  - A Splendid Gypsy; John Drew by Peggy Wood., 1927 (Box 22)
    General note
    Addenda (Nelson - Supplement).
  - "The Story of Our Time" in Encyclopedia Year Book., 1947 (Box 22)
    Includes Footlights Are Shining More Brightly by Ralph Nelson.
  - Theatre Arts Magazine., September 1943 (Box 6)
    Includes "Mail Call" by Aviation Cadet Ralph Nelson.
  - "Mail Call" by Aviation Cadet Ralph Nelson., (3 copies) (Box 6)
  - Books. (Box 101, 103, 107-109, 113, 115-121, 126-132)
  - Tapes. (Box 100, 102, 133-134)
  - Books and tapes. (Box 114)
  - Books and Tapes Used for Research
    - Brooks, Juanita. The Mountain Meadows Massacre. Norman, Oklahoma: University of Oklahoma Press., [1964] (Box 46)
    - Drayton, Mary. The Playroom. New York: Random House., [1966] (Box 46)
    - Furniss, Norman. The Mormon Conflict. New Haven: Yale University Press., 1960 (Box 46)
    - McGivern, William P. Police Special. New York: Dodd, Mead & Company., 1962 (Box 46)
    - Vetterli, Richard. Mormonism, Americanism and Politics. Salt Lake City: Ensign Publishing Company., [1961] (Box 46)
    - Counterpoint., (2 Tapes) (Box 46)
      Used for orchestral music (Schubert, Beethoven, Tschaikowsky, performed by the Los Angeles Philharmonic.
  - Close It Up! Magazine article. (Box 25)
- Audio Records
  - Aladdin. (Box 1)
    Private Edition - preview of the Cole Porter songs.
  - Proof recordings (12) - Judy Garland. (Box 20)
  - We're ready., (78 rpm records in album) (Box 141)
- Scrapbooks
  - War Plays by Ralph Nelson., 1943-1946 (Box 90)
    Clippings, photographs, letters, reviews.
  - Reviews, (Mounted in scrapbooks)
    - Reviews of various productions of Ralph Nelson. (Box 92)
  - Clippings and Articles from the Following Movies, etc., (4 Large Scrapbooks, 1 black and 3 olive) (Box 95, Box 96)
    - Black Scrapbook - Miscellaneous. (Box 96)
      Wrath of God.
      Charly.
    - Olive Scrapbook no.1. (Box 95)
      Tick...tick...tick...
      Soldier Blue.
      General.
    - Olive Scrapbook no.2. (Box 95)
      Flight of the Doves.
    - Olive Scrapbook no.3. (Box 95)
      Wrath of God (continued).
      The Wilby Conspiracy.
      Embryo.
- Taped Shows
  - Judy Garland Show - Sings 8 Songs: (Box 90)
    "I Feel a Song Coming on.".
    "I Will Come Back.".
    "Last Night When We Were Young.".
    "Life is Just a Bowl of Cherries.".
    "Dirty Hands.".
    "Pete's Blues.".
    "Come Rain, Come Shine.".
    "April Showers.".
- Scripts and Related Materials
  - Charly (Box 61-68, 73, 123)
    See also: Box 96.
    - Charly Production Files (Box 61, Box 62, Box 63, Box 64, Box 65)
      Received September 1972
      - A - C. (Box 61)
      - D - P. (Box 61)
      - P (continued) - R. (Box 62)
      - R (continued) - S. (Box 63)
      - S (continued). (Box 64)
      - S (continued) - Z. (Box 65)
    - Miscellaneous Materials (Box 66, Box 67, Box 68)
      - Scripts. (Box 66, Box 67, Box 68)
      - Research. (Box 67)
      - Stills. (Box 67, Box 68)
      - Tapes. (Box 67)
      - Books. (Box 67)
    - Publisher's script. (Box 123)
    - Miscellaneous materials. (Box 73)
      Correspondence - General.
      Legal agreements - deal memos.
      Petty Cash.
  - Lilies of the Field (Box 11-15, 33-34, 70, 76, 90, 92-94, 97, 122, 124-125, 147)
    See also: Boxes 97-99
    - Lilies of the Field. (Box 11, Box 12)
      All correspondence, business and general, including expenses, form letters, personal files, finances, censorship, legal, insurance, lists, research material, publicity, technical, pertaining to the production of Lilies of the Field.
      This is an invaluable breakdown and possibly the most complete breakdown of the actual production and duties of a producer. These files could actually serve as a course in motion picture production for the graduate student and would fill a tremendous gap in the present-day curriculum at any university.
    - Production stills. (Box 13)
    - Scripts. (Box 13, Box 14, Box 15)
      1 copy (128pp.) written by Ralph Nelson and James Poe, with all changes by Ralph Nelson.
      1 copy submitted to the Writer's Guild for arbitration indicating material actually written by James Poe and material actually written by Ralph Nelson; in the main holographic.
      12 mimeographed shooting scripts.*.
      Notes between Ralph Nelson and James Poe on arbitration over Lilies of the Field (Original and copies).
      File of James Poe's scene rewrites with holographic notes.
      James Poe's forced draft (Copy with holographic notes).
      *1 copy returned to Mr. Nelson, May 7, 1967 (BW)
    - Lilies of the Field (motion picture). (Box 33, Box 34)
      Material received December 1968.
    - Lilies of the Field., (1 copy) (Box 70)
    - Lilies of the Field (Box 76)
      Legal Agreements - deal memos (1962-1970).
      Legal Agreements - deal memos (1971-1975).
      Miscellaneous (Schedules, financial statements).
      William Barrett.
      Interview with Sidney Poitier and Ralph Nelson.
      Financial examination of United Artists.
      Allocations - Doug Netter.
      Dramatic rights.
      Participations/distribution.
      Foreign taxes.
      DGA/Pension Plan.
      Ziegler/Ross Agency.
      Trailer & Cutting Continuity.
      Theatrical re-release.
      Television.
      Publicity.
      Look to the Lilies, Broadway Musical.
    - Lilies of the Field (Original soundtrack recording). (Box 90)
    - Scrapbooks (Box 92, 93, 97)
      - Reviews from British and Irish publications. (Box 97)
      - Domestic reviews. (Box 93)
      - Foreign reviews. (Box 92)
    - Set model of the church in Lilies of the Field., (Approximately 16 × 10 × 9", made of cardboard and wood) (Box 94)
    - Final shooting script., November 26, 1962 (Box 124)
    - Final shooting script (original)., November 6, 1962 (Box 124)
    - Story outlines for future episode., (3 items) (Box 124)
    - Stills., (7 items) (Box 125)
    - Originial Lilies of the Field stills., (8 items) (Box 125)
    - The Lilies of the Field by William E. Barrett. New York: Popular Library., [1963]; (Paperback copy) (Box 125)
    - Ad copy layout., (Mounted) (Box 147)
    - Sequels to Lilies of the Field by John McGreevey and Ralph Nelson., 1978-1979 (Box 124)
      - Christmas lilies by John McGreevey., June 21, 1978; (2 copies) (Box 124)
      - Christmas lilies., June 20, 1979 (Box 124)
      - Easter lilies., August 9, 1979 (Box 124)
      - Lilies for Christmas., August 9, 1979 (Box 124)
      - Christmas Lilies of the Field., August 27, 1979 (Box 124)
      - Christmas Lilies of the Field., September 3, 1979 (Box 124)
        Final shooting script.
    - Christmas Lilies of the Field (Box 122, 124-125)
      - Stills., (1 envelope, 9 photos) (Box 124)
      - Color slides., (7 items) (Box 125)
      - Press clippings., 1979; (2 envelopes) (Box 125)
      - Production files. (Box 122, 125)
      - [Miscellaneous]. (Box 122)
        Untitled folder (removed from orange binder).
        Budget.
        Osmond (includes music).
        Cast.
        Ralph Nelson - call sheets.
        Ralph Nelson - production reports.
        Ralph Nelson - script supervisor's reports.
        Legal work.
        Lilies of the Field (TV series).
        Travel arrangements.
        Script.
        Correspondence.
        Research.
        Players' contracts.
        Petty cash.
        Crew.
        Contracts.
        Sets.
      - [No further description available]., (4 folders) (Box 125)
      - [No further description available]. (Box 125)
        With notes by Ralph Nelson.
  - Junior Miss (CBS-TV Production), by Ralph Nelson. (Box 3)
    Containing The Director's working script with holographic notes, original music by Burton Lane, and original sketches for Junior Miss sets.
  - Aladdin (CBS-TV production), directed by Ralph Nelson., 1958 (Box 1)
    Containing The Director's working script and the original words and music by Cole Porter.
  - The Man in the Dog Suit. (Box 9)
    Director's working script.
  - This Happy Breed (CBS-TV production)., 1956 (Box 4)
  - Fate is the Hunter. (Box 8)
    Director's working and shooting script and notes, original sketches including breakdown, working script and six other scripts.
  - Doyle Against the House (Dick Powell anthology). (Box 2)
  - John J. Diggs (Dick Powell anthology). (Box 9)
  - Three Soldiers (Dick Powell anthology). (Box 4)
  - Cinderella., 1957 (Box 2)
    Director's working script - completely anotated.
  - Cinderella (CBS-TV production)., 1957 (Box 1)
    Graduate study by Harold Messing, Stanford University
  - Requiem for a Heavyweight (Playhouse 90)., 1956 (Box 18)
  - Requiem for a Heavyweight (feature motion picture). Columbia Pictures., 1961 (Box 18)
  - The White Barrier by Don Hart and Ralph Nelson., 1938 (Box 4)
    Shooting script.
  - Soldier in the Rain by Ralph Nelson., 1963 (Box 4)
    Treatment and shooting script.
  - Winter Dreams by F. Scott Fitzgerald. (Box 4)
    Television script - director's working and shooting scripts. Also final script.
  - The Richest Man in Bogota (DuPont Show of The Week)., 1962 (Box 3)
    Shooting script, CBS memos, NBC memos, notes, cast comments. Also, The Country of the Blind - casting notes.
  - The Man in the Funny Suit (Desilu Playhouse)., 1960 (Box 16, Box 17)
    All developments of the script, with holographic notes, from original outline through various rewrites to final shooting script; plus all production memos, letters, production pictures, original set drawings, schedule and breakdown.
  - The Big Wheel - a play by Ralph Nelson. (Box 1)
    Original typed script and 4 copies with changes.
  - Jerry Lewis Enterprises presents Jerry Lewis as The Jazz Singer. (Box 2)
    Director's working script, completely anotated - signed by Jerry Lewis.
  - Climax Television Series (1 of 2)., 1957 (Box 5)
    Shooting scripts and budget breakdowns:
    "The Trail of Terror.".
    "Murder is a Witch.".
    "The Giant Killer.".
    "King of the Mountain.".
    "Walk a Tightrope.".
    "Payment for Judas.".
    "Locked in Fear.".
    "The Trial of Captain Wirz.".
  - Climax Television Series (2 of 2)., 1957 (Box 6)
    "Keep Me in Mind.".
    "Tunnel of Fear.".
    "The Largest City in Captivity.".
    "Murder Has a Deadline.".
    "Two Tests on Tuesday.".
  - The Director - file of correspondence. (Box 2)
    Between Rod Serling and Ralph Nelson in regards to the television play The Director written by Rod Serling, including 3 copies of the script, The Director.
  - Trial Without End by Mervin Girard with holographic notes and changes. (Box 20)
  - Father Goose. (Box 9, Box 10)
    Director's working copy of screenplay with notes, drawings, directorial suggestions to Cary Grant and Leslie Caron, and 1 copy of final shooting script.
  - Scripts (Box 69, Box 70, Box 71)
    - Arrow in the sun., (4 copies) (Box 69)
    - The battle horns., (1 copy) (Box 69)
    - Flight of the doves., (5 copies, various revisions) (Box 70)
    - The playroom., (2 copies) (Box 70)
    - The seven file., (2 copies) (Box 71)
    - Soldier Blue., (2 copies) (Box 71)
      1 copy is Ralph Nelson's working script and notes.
    - Tick...tick...tick., (2 copies) (Box 71)
  - Lady of the house - Breakdown sheet. (Box 96)
  - You can't go home again., (1 envelope) (Box 123)
    Miscellaneous files.
  - You can't go home again. (Box 123)
  - The bell jar. (Box 123)
    Budget, correspondence.
  - Because he's my friend. (Box 123)
  - Scripts and Related Materials, Arranged by Title
    (Material received December 1968)
    - "Aladdin" (television), The Dupont Show of the Month. (Box 24)
    - "Angels Weep". A play in 3 acts. (Box 24)
    - Armstrong Circle Theatre (television). (Box 24)
    - "Baby and Me" (television). (Box 24)
    - "The Big Slide" (television), CBS - Playhouse 90. (Box 24)
    - "Brandenburg Gate" (television), Motorola Hour. (Box 24)
    - "A Brief Madness" (screenplay). (Box 24)
    - "The Camel Command" (screenplay). (Box 25)
    - "The Challenge of Hemp Brown" (television), Front Row Center. (Box 25)
    - "Cinderella" (television). (Box 25)
    - "The Circular Staircase" (television), Climax. (Box 25)
    - Counterpoint (screenplay). (Box 25, Box 26, Box 27, Box 28)
    - "Deadlock" (television), CBS Front Row Center series. (Box 29)
    - Duel At Diablo (motion picture). (Box 29, Box 30, Box 31, Box 32)
    - "Explosion" (television), Armstrong Circle Theatre. (Box 32)
    - Exposé (television). (Box 32)
    - Fate is the Hunter (motion picture). (Box 32)
    - Father Goose (motion picture). (Box 32)
    - "Finlay's Fan Club" (television), CBS Front Row Center. (Box 33)
    - "Fury At Dawn" (television), Climax. (Box 33)
    - "The Greek Case" (television), Playhouse 90. (Box 33)
    - "Hamlet" (television), Dupont Show of the Month. (Box 33)
    - "Inferno" (television), The Dick Powell Show. (Box 33)
    - "Innocent Witness" (television), Front Row Center. (Box 33)
    - "The Jazz Singer" (television), Ford Startime Theatre. (Box 33)
    - Jody and Me (television). (Box 33)
    - "Judy Garland Special" (television), General Electric Theatre. (Box 33)
    - Junior Miss (television). (Box 33)
    - "Justice" (television), ABC Album. (Box 33)
    - A Lion Is in the Streets (motion picture). (Box 35)
    - "Love Is Blind" (radio), The Clock. (Box 35)
    - "Made In Heaven" (television), Playhouse 90. (Box 35)
    - "The Man in the Funny Suit" (television), Desilu Playhouse. (Box 35)
    - Man of La Mancha (musical play). (Box 35)
    - March of Dimes Show (television). (Box 35)
    - Mister Doc (television). (Box 35)
    - Mama (television). (Box 36)
    - Not Without Character (short story and play). (Box 37)
    - "The Nutcracker." Ballet performed for Playhouse 90 (television). (Box 37)
    - Once a Thief (motion picture). (Box 37, Box 38, Box 39)
    - "One Coat of White" (television), Playhouse 90. (Box 39)
    - "Outlaw's Reckoning" (television), Motorola Hour. (Box 39)
    - "Phone Call For Mathew Quade" (television), Climax. (Box 39)
    - Pied Pipers (motion picture). (Box 39, Box 40)
    - Playhouse 90. Unmounted promotional kits. (Box 40)
    - The Playroom (motion picture). (Box 40)
    - "The Playroom" (television), Front Row Center. (Box 40)
    - "Requiem for a Heavyweight" (television), Playhouse 90. (Box 41)
    - The Robert Von Kuznick Story. (Box 41)
    - "The Scandal That Rocket Paris" (television), Armstrong Circle Theatre. (Box 41)
    - Second Entrance. A play (for television). (Box 41)
    - The Seven File (motion picture). (Box 41, Box 42)
    - "Snowshoes" (television), Playhouse 90. (Box 42)
    - Soldier In the Rain (motion picture). (Box 42)
    - This Happy Breed (television). (Box 42)
    - Utah War (motion picture). (Box 42)
    - Volpone (adapted for television). (Box 42)
    - We're Ready (musical play). (Box 42)
    - The Wind is Ninety (a play). (Box 42)
    - "Winter Dreams" (television), Front Row Center. (Box 42)
    - "The World of Mort Saul" (television). (Box 42)
- Business Files
  Correspondence, etc.
  - American Braodcasting Company. (Box 43)
  - Mort Abrahams. (Box 43)
  - David Alber. (Box 43)
  - Ted Ashley. (Box 43)
  - Lloyd Almiral. (Box 43)
  - Blowitz, Thomas and Canton., 1962-1964 (Box 43)
  - CBS Television. (Box 43)
  - Ralph Nelson - Contracts. (Box 43)
  - Director's assignment sheets. (Box 43)
  - Fred Engel. (Box 44)
  - Carol Irwin. (Box 44)
  - Letters To Ralph Nelson from the Following People: (Box 44)
    Thornton Wilder (1 letter).
    Alfred Lunt (2 letters).
    Katherine Hepburn (1 letter).
    Fred Allen (3 letters).
    Alistair Cooke (1 letter).
    Noël Coward (1 letter).
    Richard Aldrich (1 letter).
    Peggy Wood (4 letters).
    Debbie Reynolds (1 letter).
    Ilka Chase (1 letter).
  - Live television lenses. (Box 44)
  - MCA. (Box 44)
  - William Morris Agency. (Box 44)
  - National Broadcasting Company. (Box 44)
  - NTA. (Box 44)
  - The National Foundation. (Box 44)
  - Petty Cash. (Box 44)
  - Hubbel Robinson. (Box 44)
  - Miscellaneous reviews and clippings. (Box 44)
- Paintings, Photographs, and Pictorial Materials
  - Presentation Photographs (Box 91)
    - Photograph of the "Emmy" signed by Martin Manulis. (Box 91)
    - From Alfred Lunt and Lynn Fontanne to Ralph Nelson. (Box 23)
    - From Red Skelton, Snub Polland, Heini Conklin, Chester Conklin, Clarence Hennecke to Ralph Nelson., (8 × 10", framed) (Box 91)
    - From Jacques Bergerac, Sheila Bond And Phyllis Kirk to Ralph Nelson., (8 × 10", framed) (Box 91)
    - From Lief Ericson, Claudette Colbert and Paul Henreid to Ralph Nelson., (8 × 10", framed) (Box 91)
    - From John Carradine, Barry Sullivan, Marilyn Maxwell, Stu Erwin, Wally Ford and Harpo Marx to Ralph Nelson., (8 × 10, framed) (Box 91)
  - Hume Cronyn and Jessica Tandy, unsigned., (8 × 10", framed) (Box 23)
    Removed from frame.
  - Production Stills, (Over 550 items) (Box 13, 18, 23, 45, 96-99)
    - Father Goose. (Box 9)
    - Requiem for a Heavyweight., (140 8 × 10 stills) (Box 18)
      Addenda.
    - From Day Before Atlanta (Playhouse 90). (Box 23)
    - Cinderella. (Box 23)
    - Winter Dreams. (Box 23)
    - Fate is the Hunter. (Box 23)
    - I Remember Mama. (Box 23)
    - Soldier in the Rain at $1.00 each (Box 23)
    - Mounted production stills: (Box 45)
      The Giant Killer.
      King of the Mountain.
      Walk a Tightrope.
      Payment for Judas.
      Trial of Terror.
      Once a Thief.
    - Production stills: (Box 97, Box 98, Box 99)
      Requiem for a Heavyweight.
      Lilies of the Field (includes 5 mounted stills).
      Duel at Diablo.
      Counterpoint.
      Cinderella.
    - Soldier Blue stills., (150 pictures) (Box 96)
  - Contact prints, no.1-169 & 170-273., (2 Large binders) (Box 96)
    Also includes stills of luncheon for Joe Levine February 16, 1970.
  - For Ralph Nelson from the Crew of Requiem for a Heavyweight., December 1961; (1 Large Brown binder) (Box 96)
  - Ralph Nelson Australian Visit., 1971; (1 Large Blue binder) (Box 96)
  - Mounted cast photographs. (Box 97, Box 98, Box 99)
    Two Tests on Tuesday.
    Tunnel of Fear.
    The Greer Case.
    Cabin B-B.
    Murder is a Witch.
    Locked in Fear.
    Keep Me in Mind.